<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hong YAN</title>
    <link>http://localhost:3435/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:3435/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Hong YAN</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:3435/media/logo_hu1d83199708a50fd4c53e13eca8c00a26_25788_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url>
      <title>Hong YAN</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title> OncoSexome: a multifaceted knowledge base of the sex-based difference in oncological drug response, molecular biomarker, risk factor, and host microbiome</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/publications/oncosexome-a-multifaceted-knowledge-base-of-the-sex-based-difference-in-oncological-drug-response-molecular-biomarker-risk-factor-and-host-microbiome/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/publications/oncosexome-a-multifaceted-knowledge-base-of-the-sex-based-difference-in-oncological-drug-response-molecular-biomarker-risk-factor-and-host-microbiome/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The NIH policy on sex as biological variable (SABV) emphasized the importance of sex-based differences in precision oncology. Over 50% of clinically actionable oncology genes are sex-biased, indicating differences in drug efficacy. Research has identified sex differences in non-reproductive cancers, highlighting the need for comprehensive sex-based cancer data. We therefore developed OncoSexome, a multidimensional knowledge base describing sex-based differences in cancer (&lt;a href=&#34;https://idrblab.org/OncoSexome/&#34;&gt;https://idrblab.org/OncoSexome/&lt;/a&gt;) across four key topics: antineoplastic drugs and responses (SDR), oncology-related biomarkers (SBM), risk factors (SRF) and microbial landscape (SML). SDR covers sex-based differences in 2051 anticancer drugs; SBM describes 12 551 sex-differential biomarkers; SRF illustrates 350 sex-dependent risk factors; SML demonstrates 1386 microbes with sex-differential abundances associated with cancer development. OncoSexome is unique in illuminating multifaceted influences of biological sex on cancer, providing both external and endogenous contributors to cancer development and describing sex-based differences for the broadest oncological classes. Given the increasing global research interest in sex-based differences, OncoSexome is expected to impact future precision oncology practices significantly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nucleic Acids Research&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Acetaminophen Use in Pregnancy: A Comparison of Self-Reported Intake with Maternal and Newborn Biomarker Measures</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/publications/acetaminophen-use-in-pregnancy-a-comparison-of-self-reported-intake-with-maternal-and-newborn-biomarker-measures/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/publications/acetaminophen-use-in-pregnancy-a-comparison-of-self-reported-intake-with-maternal-and-newborn-biomarker-measures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Acetaminophen (N-acetyl-p-aminophenol (APAP)), also known as paracetamol, is the most common over-the-counter medication taken during pregnancy to relieve fever, pain, or discomfort.1 In the USA and Europe, it was estimated that 50–65% of women reported using APAP at least once during pregnancy, with about 20% taking APAP in all three trimesters.2 Despite the high prevalence of APAP intake in pregnancy, long-term safety data concerning offspring health are limited. The exact mechanism explaining the therapeutic effects of APAP is not fully understood.3 APAP may act upon the inhibition of cyclooxygenase (COX) enzymes and prostaglandin synthesis, the endocannabinoid system, or the serotonergic pathways in the brain, for exerting its pain-relieving and fever-reducing effects.1 Recently, adverse effects of APAP exposure on fetal development have been raised. Studies have reported that APAP and its metabolites can cross the human placental barrier exposing the fetus during critical period of development. The APAP-induced oxidative stress is amplified during fetal life because of the main pathways for APAP metabolism is not active in the fetus until mid-gestation, and that sex-specific endocrine-disruptive effects of APAP are reported in animal studies.1&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A growing body of epidemiological research have investigated the associations between prenatal exposure to APAP and adverse reproductive or neurological outcomes in childhood.1 However, previous epidemiological studies have predominantly relied on using self-reported data or single-biomarker measurements to characterize APAP exposure, raising concerns over exposure misclassification.3 On one hand, self-reported maternal intakes are susceptible to under-reporting or recall bias. On the other hand, APAP metabolites have a short half-life (ie, &amp;lt;4 hours), thus a single biological measurement may only reflect recent or frequent intake. To address this methodological concern and advance our understanding of the assessment of prenatal APAP exposure, we conducted a study to compare three APAP metabolite levels in paired maternal urine and cord blood samples, and maternal self-reported frequent APAP intake data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Clinical Epidemiology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fluorinated liquid crystal monomer (FLCM) induces kidney dysfunction by disrupting PPARα-mediated fatty acid oxidation: In vivo, in vitro, and in silico assays</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/publications/fluorinated-liquid-crystal-monomer-flcm-induces-kidney-dysfunction-by-disrupting-ppar%CE%B1-mediated-fatty-acid-oxidation-in-vivo-in-vitro-and-in-silico-assays/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/publications/fluorinated-liquid-crystal-monomer-flcm-induces-kidney-dysfunction-by-disrupting-ppar%CE%B1-mediated-fatty-acid-oxidation-in-vivo-in-vitro-and-in-silico-assays/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fluorinated liquid crystal monomers (FLCMs) are ubiquitous in our daily life as being the units of liquid crystal displays, yet their toxicological impacts remain largely unexplored. Herein, this study presents a comprehensive investigation into the hazardous effects of 3,4-difluoro-4′-(trans-4-ethylcyclohexyl)-biphenyl (DFECB), a representative biphenyl FLCM, using in. vivo, in vitro, and in silico approaches. Mice exposed to human-relevant concentrations of DFECB for 30 days exhibited renal dysfunction, characterized by interstitial inflammation, glomerular morphological changes and metabolic disorders. Metabolomic profiling revealed inhibited fatty acid β-oxidation as a key factor in renal impairment, correlating with significant downregulation of peroxisome proliferator-activated receptor α (PPARα). In vitro assays demonstrated DFECB-induced cytotoxicity, oxidative stress, inflammation and energy deficit in renal cells. Importantly, pretreatment with the PPARα agonist mitigated the adverse effects of DFECB, underscoring the central role of PPARα in DFECB-induced nephrotoxicity. Molecular docking simulations elucidated strong halogen and hydrophobic interactions between DFECB and PPARα, providing mechanistic insights. Collectively, these results suggested that DFECB could act as a disruptor of the PPARα-mediated fatty acid metabolism pathway, leading to renal dysfunction. This study highlights the potential health risks associated with FLCMs and emphasizes the need for their scientific regulation and further toxicological investigation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Environmental Chemistry and Ecotoxicology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mechanistic insights into the neurotoxicity of F53B: Effects on metabolic dysregulation and apoptosis of dopaminergic neurons</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/publications/mechanistic-insights-into-the-neurotoxicity-of-f53b-effects-on-metabolic-dysregulation-and-apoptosis-of-dopaminergic-neurons/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/publications/mechanistic-insights-into-the-neurotoxicity-of-f53b-effects-on-metabolic-dysregulation-and-apoptosis-of-dopaminergic-neurons/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;F53B (6:2 chlorinated polyfluorinated ether sulfonate), a substitute for perfluorooctane sulfonate (PFOS), is widely used as a chromium mist inhibitor in the electroplating industry. However, significant concern has arisen owing to its biological toxicity. Several studies on F53B toxicity in mammals have focused on hepatotoxicity, immunotoxicity, developmental toxicity, and reproductive toxicity, while its neurotoxic effects, especially in relation to neurodegenerative diseases such as Parkinson’s disease (PD), remain unclear. In this study, we investigated the neurotoxic effects of F53B on dopaminergic neurons and explored its potential risk associated with PD in a cellular model. Potential target prediction and validation experiments demonstrated that F53B induced apoptosis in dopaminergic neurons. We also discovered that F53B triggered oxidative stress and inflammatory responses, and stimulated nitric oxide (NO) generation in the PD cellular model. Subsequently, untargeted metabolomics and lipidomics approaches were integrated to explore the molecular mechanisms underlying the response of dopaminergic neurons to F53B exposure. The results suggested that F53B disrupted arginine and proline metabolism, energy metabolism, and caused lipid dysregulation, particularly promoting the hydrolysis of sphingomyelin (SM) into ceramide (Cer). Overall, this study provides evidence that F53B exposure could increase the potential risk of PD and offers novel insights into its neurotoxicity mechanisms.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal of Hazardous Materials&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Integration of Animal Behavioral Assessment and Convolutional Neural Network to Study Wasabi-Alcohol Taste-Smell Interaction</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/publications/integration-of-animal-behavioral-assessment-and-convolutional-neural-network-to-study-wasabi-alcohol-taste-smell-interaction/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/publications/integration-of-animal-behavioral-assessment-and-convolutional-neural-network-to-study-wasabi-alcohol-taste-smell-interaction/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The commercial wasabi pastes commonly used for food preparation contain a homologous compound of chemosensory isothiocyanates (ITCs) that elicit an irritating sensation upon consumption. The impact of sniffing dietary alcoholic beverages on the sensation of wasabi spiciness has never been studied. While most sensory evaluation studies focus on individual food and beverages separately, there is a lack of research on the olfactory study of sniffing liquor while consuming wasabi. Here, a methodology is developed that combines the use of an animal behavioral study and a convolutional neural network to analyze the facial expressions of mice when they simultaneously sniff liquor and consume wasabi. The results demonstrate that the trained and validated deep learning model recognizes 29% of the images depicting co-treatment of wasabi and alcohol belonging to the class of the wasabi-negative liquor-positive group without the need for prior training materials filtering. Statistical analysis of mouse grimace scale scores obtained from the selected video frame images reveals a significant difference (P &amp;lt; 0.01) between the presence and absence of liquor. This finding suggests that dietary alcoholic beverages might have a diminishing effect on the wasabi-elicited reactions in mice. This combinatory methodology holds potential for individual ITC compound screening and sensory analyses of spirit components in the future. However, further study is required to investigate the underlying mechanism of alcohol-induced suppression of wasabi pungency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal of Visualized Experiments&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bioinformatics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/journal_referee/bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/journal_referee/bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cancer Research</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/journal_referee/cancer-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/journal_referee/cancer-research/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Communications Biology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/journal_referee/communications_biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/journal_referee/communications_biology/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genomics, Proteomics &amp; Bioinformatics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/journal_referee/genomics_proteomics_bioinformatics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/journal_referee/genomics_proteomics_bioinformatics/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>International Journal of Medical Sciences</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/journal_referee/international-journal-of-medical-sciences/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/journal_referee/international-journal-of-medical-sciences/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nature Communications</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/journal_referee/nature_communications/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/journal_referee/nature_communications/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PLOS one</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/journal_referee/plos-one/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/journal_referee/plos-one/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Redox Biology</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/journal_referee/redox-biology/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/journal_referee/redox-biology/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RSC advances</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/journal_referee/rsc-advances/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/journal_referee/rsc-advances/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Growth characteristics of HCT116 xenografts lacking asparagine synthetase vary according to sex</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/publications/growth-characteristics-of-hct116-xenografts-lacking-asparagine-synthetase-vary-according-to-sex/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/publications/growth-characteristics-of-hct116-xenografts-lacking-asparagine-synthetase-vary-according-to-sex/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;background&#34;&gt;Background&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sex-related differences in colorectal (CRC) incidence and mortality are well-documented. However, the impact of sex on metabolic pathways that drive cancer growth is not well understood. High expression of asparagine synthetase (ASNS) is associated with inferior survival for female CRC patients only. Here, we used a CRISPR/Cas9 technology to generate HCT116 ASNS−/− and HCT 116 ASNS+/+ cancer cell lines. We examine the effects of ASNS deletion on tumor growth and the subsequent rewiring of metabolic pathways in male and female Rag2/IL2RG mice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human Genomics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perfluorooctanesulfonic Acid and Perfluorooctanoic Acid Promote Migration of Three-Dimensional Colorectal Cancer Spheroids</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/publications/perfluorooctanesulfonic-acid-and-perfluorooctanoic-acid-promote-migration-of-three-dimensional-colorectal-cancer-spheroids./</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/publications/perfluorooctanesulfonic-acid-and-perfluorooctanoic-acid-promote-migration-of-three-dimensional-colorectal-cancer-spheroids./</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Perfluorooctanesulfonic acid (PFOS) and perfluorooctanoic acid (PFOA) are persistent environmental contaminants that are of increasing public concern worldwide. However, their relationship with colorectal cancer (CRC) is poorly understood. This study aims to comprehensively investigate the effect of PFOS and PFOA on the development and progression of CRC in vitro using a series of biological techniques and metabolic profiling. Herein, the migration of three-dimensional (3D) spheroids of two CRC cell lines, SW48 KRAS wide-type (WT) and SW48 KRAS G12A, were observed after exposure to PFOS and PFOA at 2 μM and 10 μM for 7 days. The time and dose-dependent migration phenotype induced by 10 μM PFOS and PFOA was further confirmed by wound healing and trans-well migration assays. To investigate the mechanism of action, derivatization-mass spectrometry-based metabolic profiles were examined from 3D spheroids of SW48 cell lines exposed to PFOS and PFOA (2 μM and 10 μM). Our findings revealed this exposure altered epithelial-mesenchymal transition related metabolic pathways, including fatty acid β-oxidation and synthesis of proteins, nucleotides, and lipids. Furthermore, this phenotype was confirmed by the downregulation of E-cadherin and upregulation of N-cadherin and vimentin. These findings show novel insight into the relationship between PFOS, PFOA, and CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Environmental Science &amp;amp; Technology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🎉 Easily create your own simple yet highly customizable blog</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/talks/get-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/talks/get-started/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Welcome 👋&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;details class=&#34;print:hidden xl:hidden&#34; open&gt;
  &lt;summary&gt;Table of Contents&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;text-sm&#34;&gt;
  &lt;nav id=&#34;TableOfContents&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#get-started&#34;&gt;Get Started&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#crowd-funded-open-source-software&#34;&gt;Crowd-funded open-source software&lt;/a&gt;
      &lt;ul&gt;
        &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#-click-here-to-become-a-sponsor-and-help-support-hugo-bloxs-future-httpshugobloxcomsponsor&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hugoblox.com/sponsor/&#34;&gt;❤️ Click here to become a sponsor and help support Hugo Blox&amp;rsquo;s future ❤️&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;/ul&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#ecosystem&#34;&gt;Ecosystem&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#inspiration&#34;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/nav&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Hugo Blox website builder for Hugo, along with its starter templates, is designed for professional creators, educators, and teams/organizations - although it can be used to create any kind of site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The template can be modified and customised to suit your needs. It&amp;rsquo;s a good platform for anyone looking to take control of their data and online identity whilst having the convenience to start off with a &lt;strong&gt;no-code solution (write in Markdown and customize with YAML parameters)&lt;/strong&gt; and having &lt;strong&gt;flexibility to later add even deeper personalization with HTML and CSS&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can work with all your favourite tools and apps with hundreds of plugins and integrations to speed up your workflows, interact with your readers, and much more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;get-started&#34;&gt;Get Started&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;👉 &lt;a href=&#34;https://hugoblox.com/templates/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create a new site&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;📚 &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.hugoblox.com/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Personalize your site&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;💬 &lt;a href=&#34;https://discord.gg/z8wNYzb&#34;&gt;Chat with the &lt;strong&gt;Hugo Blox community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.gohugo.io&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hugo community&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;🐦 Twitter: &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/GetResearchDev&#34;&gt;@GetResearchDev&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/GeorgeCushen&#34;&gt;@GeorgeCushen&lt;/a&gt; #MadeWithHugoBlox&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;💡 &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/HugoBlox/hugo-blox-builder/issues&#34;&gt;Request a &lt;strong&gt;feature&lt;/strong&gt; or report a &lt;strong&gt;bug&lt;/strong&gt; for &lt;em&gt;Hugo Blox&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;⬆️ &lt;strong&gt;Updating Hugo Blox?&lt;/strong&gt; View the &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.hugoblox.com/reference/update/&#34;&gt;Update Guide&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/HugoBlox/hugo-blox-builder/releases&#34;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;crowd-funded-open-source-software&#34;&gt;Crowd-funded open-source software&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To help us develop this template and software sustainably under the MIT license, we ask all individuals and businesses that use it to help support its ongoing maintenance and development via sponsorship.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;-click-here-to-become-a-sponsor-and-help-support-hugo-bloxs-future-httpshugobloxcomsponsor&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hugoblox.com/sponsor/&#34;&gt;❤️ Click here to become a sponsor and help support Hugo Blox&amp;rsquo;s future ❤️&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a token of appreciation for sponsoring, you can &lt;strong&gt;unlock &lt;a href=&#34;https://hugoblox.com/sponsor/&#34;&gt;these&lt;/a&gt; awesome rewards and extra features 🦄✨&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ecosystem&#34;&gt;Ecosystem&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/GetRD/academic-file-converter&#34;&gt;Bibtex To Markdown&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/strong&gt; Automatically import publications from BibTeX&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;inspiration&#34;&gt;Inspiration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hugoblox.com/creators/&#34;&gt;Learn what other &lt;strong&gt;creators&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; are building with this template.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Page builder&lt;/strong&gt; - Create &lt;em&gt;anything&lt;/em&gt; with no-code &lt;a href=&#34;https://hugoblox.com/blocks/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;blocks&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.hugoblox.com/reference/markdown/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;elements&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Edit any type of content&lt;/strong&gt; - Blog posts, publications, talks, slides, projects, and more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Create content&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.hugoblox.com/reference/markdown/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Markdown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.hugoblox.com/getting-started/cms/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Jupyter&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.hugoblox.com/getting-started/cms/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;RStudio&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Plugin System&lt;/strong&gt; - Fully customizable &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.hugoblox.com/getting-started/customize/&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;color&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;font themes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Display Code and Math&lt;/strong&gt; - Code syntax highlighting and LaTeX math supported&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Integrations&lt;/strong&gt; - &lt;a href=&#34;https://analytics.google.com&#34;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com&#34;&gt;Disqus commenting&lt;/a&gt;, Maps, Contact Forms, and more!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Beautiful Site&lt;/strong&gt; - Simple and refreshing one-page design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Industry-Leading SEO&lt;/strong&gt; - Help get your website found on search engines and social media&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Media Galleries&lt;/strong&gt; - Display your images and videos with captions in a customizable gallery&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mobile Friendly&lt;/strong&gt; - Look amazing on every screen with a mobile friendly version of your site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-language&lt;/strong&gt; - 35+ language packs including English, 中文, and Português&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Multi-user&lt;/strong&gt; - Each author gets their own profile page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Privacy Pack&lt;/strong&gt; - Assists with GDPR&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Stand Out&lt;/strong&gt; - Bring your site to life with animation, parallax backgrounds, and scroll effects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;One-Click Deployment&lt;/strong&gt; - No servers. No databases. Only files.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo Blox and its templates come with &lt;strong&gt;automatic day (light) and night (dark) mode&lt;/strong&gt; built-in. Visitors can choose their preferred mode by clicking the sun/moon icon in the header.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.hugoblox.com/getting-started/customize/&#34;&gt;Choose a stunning &lt;strong&gt;theme&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;font&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; for your site. Themes are fully customizable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2016-present &lt;a href=&#34;https://georgecushen.com&#34;&gt;George Cushen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Released under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/HugoBlox/hugo-blox-builder/blob/main/LICENSE.md&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; license.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🧠 Sharpen your thinking with a second brain</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/talks/second-brain/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/talks/second-brain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Create a personal knowledge base and share your knowledge with your peers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo Blox web framework empowers you with one of the most flexible note-taking capabilities out there.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Create a powerful knowledge base that works on top of a local folder of plain text Markdown files.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use it as your second brain, either publicly sharing your knowledge with your peers via your website, or via a private GitHub repository and password-protected site just for yourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;mindmaps&#34;&gt;Mindmaps&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo Blox supports a Markdown extension for mindmaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With this open format, can even edit your mindmaps in other popular tools such as Obsidian.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply insert a Markdown code block labelled as &lt;code&gt;markmap&lt;/code&gt; and optionally set the height of the mindmap as shown in the example below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mindmaps can be created by simply writing the items as a Markdown list within the &lt;code&gt;markmap&lt;/code&gt; code block, indenting each item to create as many sub-levels as you need:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
```markmap {height=&#34;200px&#34;}
- Hugo Modules
  - Hugo Blox
  - blox-plugins-netlify
  - blox-plugins-netlify-cms
  - blox-plugins-reveal
```
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34; height=&#34;200px&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;- Hugo Modules
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  - Hugo Blox
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  - blox-plugins-netlify
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  - blox-plugins-netlify-cms
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  - blox-plugins-reveal
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;Anh here&amp;rsquo;s a more advanced mindmap with formatting, code blocks, and math:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
```markmap
- Mindmaps
  - Links
    - [Hugo Blox Docs](https://docs.hugoblox.com/)
    - [Discord Community](https://discord.gg/z8wNYzb)
    - [GitHub](https://github.com/HugoBlox/hugo-blox-builder)
  - Features
    - Markdown formatting
    - **inline** ~~text~~ *styles*
    - multiline
      text
    - `inline code`
    -
      ```js
      console.log(&#39;hello&#39;);
      console.log(&#39;code block&#39;);
      ```
    - Math: $x = {-b \pm \sqrt{b^2-4ac} \over 2a}$
```
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;- Mindmaps
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  - Links
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    - [Hugo Blox Docs](https://docs.hugoblox.com/)
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    - [Discord Community](https://discord.gg/z8wNYzb)
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    - [GitHub](https://github.com/HugoBlox/hugo-blox-builder)
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  - Features
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    - Markdown formatting
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    - **inline** ~~text~~ *styles*
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    - multiline
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;      text
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    - `inline code`
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    -
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;      ```js
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;      console.log(&amp;#39;hello&amp;#39;);
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;      console.log(&amp;#39;code block&amp;#39;);
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;      ```
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    - Math: $x = {-b \pm \sqrt{b^2-4ac} \over 2a}$
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;highlighting&#34;&gt;Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;mark&gt;Highlight&lt;/mark&gt; important text with &lt;code&gt;mark&lt;/code&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-html&#34; data-lang=&#34;html&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;mark&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;Highlighted text&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;mark&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;callouts&#34;&gt;Callouts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use &lt;a href=&#34;https://docs.hugoblox.com/reference/markdown/#callouts&#34;&gt;callouts&lt;/a&gt; (aka &lt;em&gt;asides&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;hints&lt;/em&gt;, or &lt;em&gt;alerts&lt;/em&gt;) to draw attention to notes, tips, and warnings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By wrapping a paragraph in &lt;code&gt;{{% callout note %}} ... {{% /callout %}}&lt;/code&gt;, it will render as an aside.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{% callout note %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;A Markdown aside is useful for displaying notices, hints, or definitions to your readers.
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{% /callout %}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;flex px-4 py-3 mb-6 rounded-md bg-primary-100 dark:bg-primary-900&#34;&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;pr-3 pt-1 text-primary-600 dark:text-primary-300&#34;&gt;
  &lt;svg height=&#34;24&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34;&gt;&lt;path fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34; stroke-width=&#34;1.5&#34; d=&#34;m11.25 11.25l.041-.02a.75.75 0 0 1 1.063.852l-.708 2.836a.75.75 0 0 0 1.063.853l.041-.021M21 12a9 9 0 1 1-18 0a9 9 0 0 1 18 0m-9-3.75h.008v.008H12z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;dark:text-neutral-300&#34;&gt;A Markdown aside is useful for displaying notices, hints, or definitions to your readers.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Or use the &lt;code&gt;warning&lt;/code&gt; callout type so your readers don&amp;rsquo;t miss critical details:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;flex px-4 py-3 mb-6 rounded-md bg-yellow-100 dark:bg-yellow-900&#34;&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;pr-3 pt-1 text-red-400&#34;&gt;
  &lt;svg height=&#34;24&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 24 24&#34;&gt;&lt;path fill=&#34;none&#34; stroke=&#34;currentColor&#34; stroke-linecap=&#34;round&#34; stroke-linejoin=&#34;round&#34; stroke-width=&#34;1.5&#34; d=&#34;M12 9v3.75m-9.303 3.376c-.866 1.5.217 3.374 1.948 3.374h14.71c1.73 0 2.813-1.874 1.948-3.374L13.949 3.378c-.866-1.5-3.032-1.5-3.898 0zM12 15.75h.007v.008H12z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;dark:text-neutral-300&#34;&gt;A Markdown aside is useful for displaying notices, hints, or definitions to your readers.&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;did-you-find-this-page-helpful-consider-sharing-it-&#34;&gt;Did you find this page helpful? Consider sharing it 🙌&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>📈 Communicate your results effectively with the best data visualizations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/talks/data-visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/talks/data-visualization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hugo Blox is designed to give technical content creators a seamless experience. You can focus on the content and Hugo Blox handles the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Use popular tools such as Plotly, Mermaid, and data frames.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;charts&#34;&gt;Charts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo Blox supports the popular &lt;a href=&#34;https://plot.ly/&#34;&gt;Plotly&lt;/a&gt; format for interactive data visualizations. With Plotly, you can design almost any kind of visualization you can imagine!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save your Plotly JSON in your page folder, for example &lt;code&gt;line-chart.json&lt;/code&gt;, and then add the &lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; chart data=&amp;quot;line-chart&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}&lt;/code&gt; shortcode where you would like the chart to appear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Demo:&lt;/p&gt;




&lt;div id=&#34;chart-237495816&#34; class=&#34;chart&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script&gt;
  async function fetchChartJSON() {
    console.debug(&#39;Hugo Blox fetching chart JSON...&#39;)
    const response = await fetch(&#39;.\/line-chart.json&#39;);
    return await response.json();
  }

  (function() {
    let a = setInterval( function() {
      if ( typeof window.Plotly === &#39;undefined&#39; ) {
        console.debug(&#39;Plotly not loaded yet...&#39;)
        return;
      }
      clearInterval( a );

      fetchChartJSON().then(chart =&gt; {
        console.debug(&#39;Plotting chart...&#39;)
        window.Plotly.newPlot(&#39;chart-237495816&#39;, chart.data, chart.layout, {responsive: true});
      });
    }, 500 );
  })();
&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You might also find the &lt;a href=&#34;http://plotly-json-editor.getforge.io/&#34;&gt;Plotly JSON Editor&lt;/a&gt; useful.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;diagrams&#34;&gt;Diagrams&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo Blox supports the &lt;em&gt;Mermaid&lt;/em&gt; Markdown extension for diagrams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example &lt;strong&gt;flowchart&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;```mermaid
graph TD
A[Hard] --&amp;gt;|Text| B(Round)
B --&amp;gt; C{Decision}
C --&amp;gt;|One| D[Result 1]
C --&amp;gt;|Two| E[Result 2]
```
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;graph TD
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;A[Hard] --&amp;gt;|Text| B(Round)
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;B --&amp;gt; C{Decision}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;C --&amp;gt;|One| D[Result 1]
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;C --&amp;gt;|Two| E[Result 2]
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;An example &lt;strong&gt;sequence diagram&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;```mermaid
sequenceDiagram
Alice-&amp;gt;&amp;gt;John: Hello John, how are you?
loop Healthcheck
    John-&amp;gt;&amp;gt;John: Fight against hypochondria
end
Note right of John: Rational thoughts!
John--&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Alice: Great!
John-&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Bob: How about you?
Bob--&amp;gt;&amp;gt;John: Jolly good!
```
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;sequenceDiagram
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Alice-&amp;gt;&amp;gt;John: Hello John, how are you?
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;loop Healthcheck
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;    John-&amp;gt;&amp;gt;John: Fight against hypochondria
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;end
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Note right of John: Rational thoughts!
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;John--&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Alice: Great!
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;John-&amp;gt;&amp;gt;Bob: How about you?
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Bob--&amp;gt;&amp;gt;John: Jolly good!
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;An example &lt;strong&gt;class diagram&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;```mermaid
classDiagram
Class01 &amp;lt;|-- AveryLongClass : Cool
Class03 *-- Class04
Class05 o-- Class06
Class07 .. Class08
Class09 --&amp;gt; C2 : Where am i?
Class09 --* C3
Class09 --|&amp;gt; Class07
Class07 : equals()
Class07 : Object[] elementData
Class01 : size()
Class01 : int chimp
Class01 : int gorilla
Class08 &amp;lt;--&amp;gt; C2: Cool label
```
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;classDiagram
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Class01 &amp;lt;|-- AveryLongClass : Cool
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Class03 *-- Class04
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Class05 o-- Class06
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Class07 .. Class08
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Class09 --&amp;gt; C2 : Where am i?
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Class09 --* C3
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Class09 --|&amp;gt; Class07
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Class07 : equals()
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Class07 : Object[] elementData
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Class01 : size()
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Class01 : int chimp
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Class01 : int gorilla
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Class08 &amp;lt;--&amp;gt; C2: Cool label
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;An example &lt;strong&gt;state diagram&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;```mermaid
stateDiagram
[*] --&amp;gt; Still
Still --&amp;gt; [*]
Still --&amp;gt; Moving
Moving --&amp;gt; Still
Moving --&amp;gt; Crash
Crash --&amp;gt; [*]
```
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-fallback&#34; data-lang=&#34;fallback&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;stateDiagram
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;[*] --&amp;gt; Still
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Still --&amp;gt; [*]
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Still --&amp;gt; Moving
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Moving --&amp;gt; Still
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Moving --&amp;gt; Crash
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;Crash --&amp;gt; [*]
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;data-frames&#34;&gt;Data Frames&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Save your spreadsheet as a CSV file in your page&amp;rsquo;s folder and then render it by adding the &lt;em&gt;Table&lt;/em&gt; shortcode to your page:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-go&#34; data-lang=&#34;go&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;{{&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;table&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;path&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;results.csv&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;header&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;true&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;caption&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;Table 1: My results&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;}}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;














&lt;table class=&#34;table-auto w-full&#34;&gt;
  
    
    
    &lt;thead&gt;
      &lt;tr&gt;  &lt;th class=&#34;border-b dark:border-slate-600 font-medium p-4 pt-0 pb-3 text-slate-400 dark:text-slate-200 text-left&#34;&gt;customer_id&lt;/th&gt;  &lt;th class=&#34;border-b dark:border-slate-600 font-medium p-4 pt-0 pb-3 text-slate-400 dark:text-slate-200 text-left&#34;&gt;score&lt;/th&gt;  &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;/thead&gt;
  
  &lt;tbody&gt;
  
    &lt;tr&gt;
      
        
          &lt;td data-table-dtype=&#34;number&#34; class=&#34;border-b border-slate-100 dark:border-slate-700 p-4 text-slate-500 dark:text-slate-400&#34;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
        
      
        
          &lt;td data-table-dtype=&#34;number&#34; class=&#34;border-b border-slate-100 dark:border-slate-700 p-4 text-slate-500 dark:text-slate-400&#34;&gt;0&lt;/td&gt;
        
      
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  
    &lt;tr&gt;
      
        
          &lt;td data-table-dtype=&#34;number&#34; class=&#34;border-b border-slate-100 dark:border-slate-700 p-4 text-slate-500 dark:text-slate-400&#34;&gt;2&lt;/td&gt;
        
      
        
          &lt;td data-table-dtype=&#34;text&#34; class=&#34;border-b border-slate-100 dark:border-slate-700 p-4 text-slate-500 dark:text-slate-400&#34;&gt;0.5&lt;/td&gt;
        
      
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  
    &lt;tr&gt;
      
        
          &lt;td data-table-dtype=&#34;number&#34; class=&#34;border-b border-slate-100 dark:border-slate-700 p-4 text-slate-500 dark:text-slate-400&#34;&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
        
      
        
          &lt;td data-table-dtype=&#34;number&#34; class=&#34;border-b border-slate-100 dark:border-slate-700 p-4 text-slate-500 dark:text-slate-400&#34;&gt;1&lt;/td&gt;
        
      
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
  
    &lt;caption class=&#34;table-caption&#34;&gt;Table 1: My results&lt;/caption&gt;
  
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;did-you-find-this-page-helpful-consider-sharing-it-&#34;&gt;Did you find this page helpful? Consider sharing it 🙌&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>👩🏼‍🏫 Teach academic courses</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/talks/teach-courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/talks/teach-courses/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://hugoblox.com&#34;&gt;Hugo Blox Builder&lt;/a&gt; is designed to give technical content creators a seamless experience. You can focus on the content and the Hugo Blox Builder which this template is built upon handles the rest.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Embed videos, podcasts, code, LaTeX math, and even test students!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On this page, you&amp;rsquo;ll find some examples of the types of technical content that can be rendered with Hugo Blox.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;video&#34;&gt;Video&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Teach your course by sharing videos with your students. Choose from one of the following approaches:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Youtube&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; youtube D2vj0WcvH5c &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;


    
    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/D2vj0WcvH5c?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;
      &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bilibili&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; bilibili BV1WV4y1r7DF &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;w-full h-auto aspect-video relative&#34;&gt;
  &lt;iframe src=&#34;//player.bilibili.com/player.html?bvid=BV1WV4y1r7DF&amp;page=1&#34;
  allow=&#34;accelerometer; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; fullscreen; picture-in-picture;&#34;
  class=&#34;w-full h-full&#34;
  &gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Video file&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Videos may be added to a page by either placing them in your &lt;code&gt;assets/media/&lt;/code&gt; media library or in your &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content-management/page-bundles/&#34;&gt;page&amp;rsquo;s folder&lt;/a&gt;, and then embedding them with the &lt;em&gt;video&lt;/em&gt; shortcode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; video src=&amp;quot;my_video.mp4&amp;quot; controls=&amp;quot;yes&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;podcast&#34;&gt;Podcast&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can add a podcast or music to a page by placing the MP3 file in the page&amp;rsquo;s folder or the media library folder and then embedding the audio on your page with the &lt;em&gt;audio&lt;/em&gt; shortcode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{&amp;lt; audio src=&amp;quot;ambient-piano.mp3&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Try it out:&lt;/p&gt;








  








&lt;audio controls &gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;http://localhost:3435/talks/teach-courses/ambient-piano.mp3&#34; type=&#34;audio/mpeg&#34;&gt;
&lt;/audio&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;test-students&#34;&gt;Test students&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Provide a simple yet fun self-assessment by revealing the solutions to challenges with the &lt;code&gt;spoiler&lt;/code&gt; shortcode:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;spoiler&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;na&#34;&gt;text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;👉 Click to view the solution&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;You found me!
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;{{&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;/&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;spoiler&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt;}}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;details class=&#34;spoiler &#34;  id=&#34;spoiler-3&#34;&gt;
  &lt;summary class=&#34;cursor-pointer&#34;&gt;👉 Click to view the solution&lt;/summary&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;rounded-lg bg-neutral-50 dark:bg-neutral-800 p-2&#34;&gt;
    You found me 🎉
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/details&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo Blox Builder supports a Markdown extension for $\LaTeX$ math. Enable math by setting the &lt;code&gt;math: true&lt;/code&gt; option in your page&amp;rsquo;s front matter, or enable math for your entire site by toggling math in your &lt;code&gt;config/_default/params.yaml&lt;/code&gt; file:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-yaml&#34; data-lang=&#34;yaml&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;features&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;  &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;math&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;    &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nt&#34;&gt;enable&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;kc&#34;&gt;true&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;w&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;To render &lt;em&gt;inline&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;block&lt;/em&gt; math, wrap your LaTeX math with &lt;code&gt;$...$&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;$$...$$&lt;/code&gt;, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example &lt;strong&gt;math block&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-latex&#34; data-lang=&#34;latex&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;sb&#34;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\gamma&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;_{n} &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\frac&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; | &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; x_{n} &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; x_{n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;} &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\right&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;^T &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\nabla&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; F &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; x_{n}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\nabla&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; F &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; x_{n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\right&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\right&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; |}{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\|\nabla&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; F&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{x}_{n}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\nabla&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; F&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\mathbf&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{x}_{n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\right&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\|&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;^&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
$$\gamma_{n} = \frac{ \left | \left (\mathbf x_{n} - \mathbf x_{n-1} \right )^T \left [\nabla F (\mathbf x_{n}) - \nabla F (\mathbf x_{n-1}) \right ] \right |}{\left \|\nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n}) - \nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n-1}) \right \|^2}$$
&lt;p&gt;Example &lt;strong&gt;inline math&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;code&gt;$\nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n})$&lt;/code&gt; renders as $\nabla F(\mathbf{x}_{n})$.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example &lt;strong&gt;multi-line math&lt;/strong&gt; using the math linebreak (&lt;code&gt;\\&lt;/code&gt;):&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-latex&#34; data-lang=&#34;latex&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;sb&#34;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;f&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;k;p_{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}^{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\begin&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{cases}p_{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}^{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;} &amp;amp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{if }k&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\\&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;-&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;p_{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;}^{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;} &amp;amp; &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\text&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{if }k&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nv&#34;&gt;\end&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nb&#34;&gt;{cases}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;$$&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
$$
f(k;p_{0}^{*}) = \begin{cases}p_{0}^{*} &amp; \text{if }k=1, \\
1-p_{0}^{*} &amp; \text{if }k=0.\end{cases}
$$
&lt;h2 id=&#34;code&#34;&gt;Code&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo Blox Builder utilises Hugo&amp;rsquo;s Markdown extension for highlighting code syntax. The code theme can be selected in the &lt;code&gt;config/_default/params.yaml&lt;/code&gt; file.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;```python
import pandas as pd
data = pd.read_csv(&amp;quot;data.csv&amp;quot;)
data.head()
```
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34; data-lang=&#34;python&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;kn&#34;&gt;import&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;pandas&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;as&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nn&#34;&gt;pd&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;pd&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;read_csv&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s2&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;data.csv&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;head&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h2 id=&#34;inline-images&#34;&gt;Inline Images&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-go&#34; data-lang=&#34;go&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;{{&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;icon&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#34;python&amp;#34;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;&amp;gt;}}&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nx&#34;&gt;Python&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
  &lt;span class=&#34;inline-block  pr-1&#34;&gt;
    &lt;svg style=&#34;height: 1em; transform: translateY(0.1em);&#34; xmlns=&#34;http://www.w3.org/2000/svg&#34; height=&#34;1em&#34; viewBox=&#34;0 0 448 512&#34; fill=&#34;currentColor&#34;&gt;&lt;path d=&#34;M439.8 200.5c-7.7-30.9-22.3-54.2-53.4-54.2h-40.1v47.4c0 36.8-31.2 67.8-66.8 67.8H172.7c-29.2 0-53.4 25-53.4 54.3v101.8c0 29 25.2 46 53.4 54.3 33.8 9.9 66.3 11.7 106.8 0 26.9-7.8 53.4-23.5 53.4-54.3v-40.7H226.2v-13.6h160.2c31.1 0 42.6-21.7 53.4-54.2 11.2-33.5 10.7-65.7 0-108.6zM286.2 404c11.1 0 20.1 9.1 20.1 20.3 0 11.3-9 20.4-20.1 20.4-11 0-20.1-9.2-20.1-20.4.1-11.3 9.1-20.3 20.1-20.3zM167.8 248.1h106.8c29.7 0 53.4-24.5 53.4-54.3V91.9c0-29-24.4-50.7-53.4-55.6-35.8-5.9-74.7-5.6-106.8.1-45.2 8-53.4 24.7-53.4 55.6v40.7h106.9v13.6h-147c-31.1 0-58.3 18.7-66.8 54.2-9.8 40.7-10.2 66.1 0 108.6 7.6 31.6 25.7 54.2 56.8 54.2H101v-48.8c0-35.3 30.5-66.4 66.8-66.4zm-6.7-142.6c-11.1 0-20.1-9.1-20.1-20.3.1-11.3 9-20.4 20.1-20.4 11 0 20.1 9.2 20.1 20.4s-9 20.3-20.1 20.3z&#34;/&gt;&lt;/svg&gt;
  &lt;/span&gt; Python&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;did-you-find-this-page-helpful-consider-sharing-it-&#34;&gt;Did you find this page helpful? Consider sharing it 🙌&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>✅ Manage your projects</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/talks/project-management/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/talks/project-management/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Easily manage your projects - create ideation mind maps, Gantt charts, todo lists, and more!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;ideation&#34;&gt;Ideation&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo Blox supports a Markdown extension for mindmaps.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Simply insert a Markdown code block labelled as &lt;code&gt;markmap&lt;/code&gt; and optionally set the height of the mindmap as shown in the example below.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Mindmaps can be created by simply writing the items as a Markdown list within the &lt;code&gt;markmap&lt;/code&gt; code block, indenting each item to create as many sub-levels as you need:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;
&lt;pre class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;
&lt;code&gt;
```markmap {height=&#34;200px&#34;}
- Hugo Modules
  - Hugo Blox
  - blox-plugins-netlify
  - blox-plugins-netlify-cms
  - blox-plugins-reveal
```
&lt;/code&gt;
&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;markmap&#34; style=&#34;height: 200px;&#34;&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;- Hugo Modules
  - Hugo Blox
  - blox-plugins-netlify
  - blox-plugins-netlify-cms
  - blox-plugins-reveal&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;diagrams&#34;&gt;Diagrams&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hugo Blox supports the &lt;em&gt;Mermaid&lt;/em&gt; Markdown extension for diagrams.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An example &lt;strong&gt;Gantt diagram&lt;/strong&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;```mermaid
gantt
section Section
Completed :done,    des1, 2014-01-06,2014-01-08
Active        :active,  des2, 2014-01-07, 3d
Parallel 1   :         des3, after des1, 1d
Parallel 2   :         des4, after des1, 1d
Parallel 3   :         des5, after des3, 1d
Parallel 4   :         des6, after des4, 1d
```
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;mermaid&#34;&gt;gantt
section Section
Completed :done,    des1, 2014-01-06,2014-01-08
Active        :active,  des2, 2014-01-07, 3d
Parallel 1   :         des3, after des1, 1d
Parallel 2   :         des4, after des1, 1d
Parallel 3   :         des5, after des3, 1d
Parallel 4   :         des6, after des4, 1d
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;todo-lists&#34;&gt;Todo lists&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can even write your todo lists in Markdown too:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34; data-lang=&#34;markdown&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;- [x]&lt;/span&gt; Write math example
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;- [x]&lt;/span&gt; Write diagram example
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;k&#34;&gt;- [ ]&lt;/span&gt; Do something else
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;p&gt;renders as&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Write math example
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input checked=&#34;&#34; disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Write diagram example&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;input disabled=&#34;&#34; type=&#34;checkbox&#34;&gt; Do something else&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;did-you-find-this-page-helpful-consider-sharing-it-&#34;&gt;Did you find this page helpful? Consider sharing it 🙌&lt;/h2&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An integrated analysis of the fecal metabolome and metagenome reveals the distinct effects of differentially charged nanoplastics on the gut microbiota-associated metabolites in mice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/publications/an-integrated-analysis-of-the-fecal-metabolome-and-metagenome-reveals-the-distinct-effects-of-differentially-charged-nanoplastics-on-the-gut-microbiota-associated-metabolites-in-mice./</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/publications/an-integrated-analysis-of-the-fecal-metabolome-and-metagenome-reveals-the-distinct-effects-of-differentially-charged-nanoplastics-on-the-gut-microbiota-associated-metabolites-in-mice./</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether nanoplastics with differential charges cause intestinal impairment via distinct mechanisms remains unclear. We investigated the relationship between fecal metabolites and the gut microbiome, and potential biomarkers thereof, in mice following exposure to differentially charged polystyrene nanoplastics (PS-NPs). Metagenomic analysis revealed that exposure to differentially charged PS-NPs resulted in alterations in the abundances of Bilophila_wadsworthia, Helicobacter apodemus, and Helicobacter typhlonius. A total of 237 fecal metabolites were significantly altered in mice that exhibited intestinal impairment, and these included 10 gut microbiota-related fecal metabolites that accurately discriminated impaired intestinal samples from the control. Additionally, the specific gut microbiome-related fecal metabolite-based model approach for the prediction of intestinal impairment in mice had an area under the curve (AUC) of 1.0 in the PS (without charge) group, an AUC of 0.94 in the PS-NH2 (positive charge) group, and an AUC of 0.86 in the PS-COOH (negative charge) group. Thus, the model showed promising evaluable accuracy for the prediction of intestinal impairment induced by nanoplastics in a charge-specific manner. Our study demonstrates that the fecal metabolome of mice with intestinal impairment following exposure to differentially charged nanoplastics is associated with changes in the gut microbiome. The identified biomarkers have potential application for the detection of intestinal impairment after exposure to negative, positive, or noncharged nanomaterials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Science of the Total Environment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Urinary Paraben Concentrations and Associations with the Periconceptional Urinary Metabolome: Untargeted and Targeted Metabolomics Analyses of Participants from the Early Pregnancy Study</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/publications/urinary-paraben-concentrations-and-associations-with-the-periconceptional-urinary-metabolome-untargeted-and-targeted-metabolomics-analyses-of-participants-from-the-early-pregnancy-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/publications/urinary-paraben-concentrations-and-associations-with-the-periconceptional-urinary-metabolome-untargeted-and-targeted-metabolomics-analyses-of-participants-from-the-early-pregnancy-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Background: Parabens, found in everyday items from personal care products to foods, are chemicals with endocrine-disrupting activity, which has been shown to influence reproductive function. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; Objectives: This study investigated whether urinary concentrations of methylparaben, propylparaben, or butylparaben were associated with the urinary metabolome during the periconceptional period, a critical window for female reproductive function. Changes to the periconceptional urinary metabolome could provide insights into the mechanisms by which parabens could impact fertility. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; Methods:
Urinary paraben concentrations were measured in paired pre- and postconception urine samples from 42 participants in the Early Pregnancy Study, a prospective cohort of 221 women attempting to conceive. We performed untargeted and targeted metabolomics analyses using ultrahigh-performance liquid chromatography quadrupole time-of-flight mass spectrometry. We used principal component analysis, orthogonal partial least-squares discriminant analysis, and permutation testing, coupled with univariate statistical analyses, to find metabolites associated with paraben concentration at the two time points. Potential confounders were identified with a directed acyclic graph and used to adjust results with multivariable linear regression. Metabolites were identified using fragmentation data. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; Results: Seven metabolites were associated with paraben concentration (variable importance to projection score &amp;gt;1, false discovery rate–corrected 𝑞-value&amp;lt;0.1). We identified four diet-related metabolites to the Metabolomics Standards Initiative (MSI) certainty of identification level 2, including metabolites from smoke flavoring, grapes, and olive oil. One metabolite was identified to the class level only (MSI level 3). Two metabolites were unidentified (MSI level 4). After adjustment, three metabolites remained associated with methylparaben and propylparaben, two of which were diet-related. No metabolomic markers of endocrine disruption were associated with paraben concentrations. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; Discussion: This study identified novel relationships between urinary paraben concentrations and diet-related metabolites but not with metabolites on endocrine-disrupting pathways, as hypothesized. It demonstrates the feasibility of integrating untargeted metabolomics data with environmental exposure information and epidemiological adjustment for confounders. The findings underscore a potentially important connection between diet and paraben exposure, with applications to nutritional epidemiology and dietary exposure assessment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Environmental Health Perspectives&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of decreased ferroptosis in male colorectal cancer patients with KRAS mutations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/publications/discovery-of-decreased-ferroptosis-in-male-colorectal-cancer-patients-with-kras-mutations-/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/publications/discovery-of-decreased-ferroptosis-in-male-colorectal-cancer-patients-with-kras-mutations-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abtract&#34;&gt;Abtract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aberrant tumor metabolism is a hallmark of cancer in which metabolic rewiring can support tumor growth under nutrient deficient conditions. KRAS mutations occur in 35–45% of all colorectal cancer (CRC) cases and are difficult to treat. The relationship between mutant KRAS and aberrant metabolism in CRCs has not been fully explored and could be a target for intervention. We previously acquired non-targeted metabolomics data from 161 tumor tissues and 39 normal colon tissues from stage I-III chemotherapy naïve CRC patients. In this study, we revealed that only in male patients, tumors with KRAS mutations had several altered pathways that suppress ferroptosis, including glutathione biosynthesis, transsulfuration activity, and methionine metabolism. To validate this phenotype, MC38 CRC cells (KRAS&lt;sup&gt;G13R&lt;/sup&gt;) were treated with a ferroptosis inducer; RAS-selected lethal (RSL3). RSL3 altered metabolic pathways in the opposite direction to that seen in KRAS mutant tumors from male patients confirming a suppressed ferroptosis metabolic phenotype in these patients. We further validated gene expression data from an additional CRC patient cohort (Gene Expression Omnibus (GEO)), and similarly observed differences in ferroptosis-related genes by sex and KRAS status. Further examination of the relationship between these genes and overall survival (OS) in the GEO cohort showed that KRAS mutant tumors are associated with poorer 5-year OS compared to KRAS wild type tumors, and only in male patients. Additionally, high compared to low expression of GPX4, FTH1, FTL, which suppress ferroptosis, were associated with poorer 5-year OS only in KRAS mutant tumors from male CRC patients. Additionally, low compared to high expression of ACSL4 was associated with poorer OS for this group. Our results show that KRAS mutant tumors from male CRC patients have suppressed ferroptosis, and gene expression changes that suppress ferroptosis associate with adverse outcomes for these patients, revealing a novel potential avenue for therapeutic approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Redox Biology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ferroptosis in colorectal cancer: a future target?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/publications/ferroptosis-in-colorectal-cancer-a-future-target/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/publications/ferroptosis-in-colorectal-cancer-a-future-target/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Colorectal cancer (CRC) is the third leading cause of cancer deaths worldwide and is characterised by frequently mutated genes, such as APC, TP53, KRAS and BRAF. The current treatment options of chemotherapy, radiation therapy and surgery are met with challenges such as cancer recurrence, drug resistance, and overt toxicity. CRC therapies exert their efficacy against cancer cells by activating biological pathways that contribute to various forms of regulated cell death (RCD). In 2012, ferroptosis was discovered as an iron-dependent and lipid peroxide-driven form of RCD. Recent studies suggest that therapies which target ferroptosis are promising treatment strategies for CRC. However, a greater understanding of the mechanisms of ferroptosis initiation, propagation, and resistance in CRC is needed. This review provides an overview of recent research in ferroptosis and its potential role as a therapeutic target in CRC. We also propose future research directions that could help to enhance our understanding of ferroptosis in CRC.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;British Journal of Cancer&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Targeting ferroptosis to treat colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/publications/targeting-ferroptosis-to-treat-colorectal-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/publications/targeting-ferroptosis-to-treat-colorectal-cancer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ferroptosis has emerged as a promising target for colorectal cancer (CRC) treatment. Although disrupting glutathione metabolism is the primary strategy for ferroptosis induction, additional key pathways link ferroptosis to CRC pathogenesis. Here, we discuss arachidonic acid (AA), energy metabolism, AMP-activated protein kinase (AMPK), phosphatidylinositol-3-kinase (PI3K)-protein kinase B (Akt)-mammalian target of rapamycin (mTOR), and Hippo signaling, summarize key findings, and propose new conceptual avenues for CRC treatment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Trends in Cell Biology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bile acid distributions, sex-specifcity, and prognosis in colorectal cancer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/publications/bile-acid-distributions-sex-specifcity-and-prognosis-in-colorectal-cancer/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/publications/bile-acid-distributions-sex-specifcity-and-prognosis-in-colorectal-cancer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Background: Bile acids are known to be genotoxic and contribute to colorectal cancer (CRC). However, the link between CRC tumor bile acids to tumor location, patient sex, microbiome, immune-regulatory cells, and prognosis is not clear. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; Methods: We conducted bile acid analysis using targeted liquid chromatography–mass spectrometry (LC–MS) on tumor tissues from CRC patients (n=228) with survival analysis. We performed quantitative immunofuorescence (QIF) on tumors to examine immune cells. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; Results: Twelve of the bile acids were signifcantly higher in right-sided colon tumors compared to left-sided colon
tumors. Furthermore, in male patients, right-sided colon tumors had elevated secondary bile acids (deoxycholic acid, lithocholic acid, ursodeoxycholic acid) compared to left-sided colon tumors, but this diference between tumors by location was not observed in females. A high ratio of glycoursodeoxycholic to ursodeoxycholic was associated with 5-year overall survival (HR=3.76, 95% CI=1.17 to 12.1, P=0.026), and a high ratio of glycochenodeoxycholic acid to chenodeoxycholic acid was associated with 5-year recurrence-free survival (HR=3.61, 95% CI=1.10 to 11.84, P=0.034). We also show correlation between these bile acids and FoxP3+T regulatory cells. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt; Conclusions: This study revealed that the distribution of bile acid abundances in colon cancer patients is tumor location-, age- and sex-specifc, and are linked to patient prognosis. This study provides new implications for targeting bile acid metabolism, microbiome, and immune responses for colon cancer patients by taking into account primary tumor location and sex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Biology of Sex Diferences&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asparagine, colorectal cancer, and the role of sex, genes, microbes, and diet: A narrative review</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/publications/asparagine-colorectal-cancer-and-the-role-of-sex-genes-microbes-and-diet-a-narrative-review/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/publications/asparagine-colorectal-cancer-and-the-role-of-sex-genes-microbes-and-diet-a-narrative-review/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Asparagine (Asn) and enzymes that catalyze the metabolism of Asn have been linked to the regulation and propagation of colorectal cancer (CRC). Increased Asn and asparagine synthetase (ASNS) expression, both contribute to CRC progression and metastasis. In contradistinction, L-asparaginase (ASNase) which breaks down Asn, exhibits an anti-tumor effect. Metabolic pathways such as KRAS/PI3K/AKT/mTORC1 signaling and high SOX12 expression can positively regulate endogenous Asn production. Conversely, the tumor suppressor, TP53, negatively impacts ASNS, thus limiting Asn synthesis and reducing tumor burden. Asn abundance can be altered by factors extrinsic to the cancer cell such as diet, the microbiome, and therapeutic use of ASNase. Recent studies have shown that sex-related factors can also influence the regulation of Asn, and high Asn production results in poorer prognosis for female CRC patients but not males. In this narrative review, we critically review studies that have examined endogenous and exogenous modulators of Asn bioavailability and summarize the key metabolic networks that regulate Asn metabolism. We also provide new hypotheses regarding sex-related influences on Asn, including the involvement of the sex-steroid hormone estrogen and estrogen receptors. Further, we hypothesize that sex-specific factors that influence Asn metabolism can influence clinical outcomes in CRC patients.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Frontiers in Molecular Biosciences&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TidyMass an object-oriented reproducible analysis framework for LC–MS data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/publications/tidymass-an-object-oriented-reproducible-analysis-framework-for-lcms-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/publications/tidymass-an-object-oriented-reproducible-analysis-framework-for-lcms-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reproducibility, traceability, and transparency have been long-standing issues for metabolomics data analysis. Multiple tools have been developed, but limitations still exist. Here, we present the tidyMass project (&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tidymass.org/)&#34;&gt;https://www.tidymass.org/)&lt;/a&gt;, a comprehensive R-based computational framework that can achieve the traceable, shareable, and reproducible workflow needs of data processing and analysis for LC-MS-based untargeted metabolomics. TidyMass is an ecosystem of R packages that share an underlying design philosophy, grammar, and data structure, which provides a comprehensive, reproducible, and object-oriented computational framework. The modular architecture makes tidyMass a highly flexible and extensible tool, which other users can improve and integrate with other tools to customize their own pipeline.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nature Communications&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Asparagine Metabolism in Tumors Is Linked to Poor Survival in Females with Colorectal Cancer: A Cohort Study</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/publications/asparagine-metabolism-in-tumors-is-linked-to-poor-survival-in-females-with-colorectal-cancer-a-cohort-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/publications/asparagine-metabolism-in-tumors-is-linked-to-poor-survival-in-females-with-colorectal-cancer-a-cohort-study/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The interplay between the sex-specific differences in tumor metabolome and colorectal cancer (CRC) prognosis has never been studied and represents an opportunity to improve patient outcomes. This study examines the link between tumor metabolome and prognosis by sex for CRC patients. Using untargeted metabolomics analysis, abundances of 91 metabolites were obtained from primary tumor tissues from 197 patients (N = 95 females, N = 102 males) after surgical colectomy for stage I-III CRC. Cox Proportional hazard (PH) regression models estimated the associations between tumor metabolome and 5-year overall survival (OS) and recurrence-free survival (RFS), and their interactions with sex. Eleven metabolites had significant sex differences in their associations with 5-year OS, and five metabolites for 5-year RFS. The metabolites asparagine and serine had sex interactions for both OS and RFS. Furthermore, in the asparagine synthetase (ASNS)-catalyzed asparagine synthesis pathway, asparagine was associated with substantially poorer OS (HR (95% CI): 6.39 (1.78–22.91)) and RFS (HR (95% CI): 4.36 (1.39–13.68)) for female patients only. Similar prognostic disadvantages in females were seen in lysophospholipid and polyamine synthesis. Unique metabolite profiles indicated that increased asparagine synthesis was associated with poorer prognosis for females only, providing insight into precision medicine for CRC treatment stratified by sex.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Metabolites&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kynurenic acid may underlie sex-specific immune responses to COVID-19</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/publications/kynurenic-acid-may-underlie-sex-specific-immune-responses-to-covid-19/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/publications/kynurenic-acid-may-underlie-sex-specific-immune-responses-to-covid-19/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Coronavirus disease 2019 (COVID-19) has poorer clinical outcomes in males than in females, and immune responses underlie these sex-related differences. Because immune responses are, in part, regulated by metabolites, we examined the serum metabolomes of COVID-19 patients. In male patients, kynurenic acid (KA) and a high KA–to–kynurenine (K) ratio (KA:K) positively correlated with age and with inflammatory cytokines and chemokines and negatively correlated with T cell responses. Males that clinically deteriorated had a higher KA:K than those that stabilized. KA inhibits glutamate release, and glutamate abundance was lower in patients that clinically deteriorated and correlated with immune responses. Analysis of data from the Genotype-Tissue Expression (GTEx) project revealed that the expression of the gene encoding the enzyme that produces KA, kynurenine aminotransferase, correlated with cytokine abundance and activation of immune responses in older males. This study reveals that KA has a sex-specific link to immune responses and clinical outcomes in COVID-19, suggesting a positive feedback between metabolites and immune responses in males.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Science Signaling&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new concept based on ensemble strategy and derivative for the quantitative analysis of infrared data</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/publications/a-new-concept-based-on-ensemble-strategy-and-derivative-for-the-quantitative-analysis-of-infrared-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/publications/a-new-concept-based-on-ensemble-strategy-and-derivative-for-the-quantitative-analysis-of-infrared-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Preprocessing and variable selection are the most widely used strategies to develop accurate predictive models based on infrared spectroscopy. In our study, a new conception that the derivative combined with ensemble strategy based on competitive adaptive reweighted sampling (CARS), stability competitive adaptive reweighted sampling (SCARS), Monte Carlo uninformative variables elimination (MCUVE), and bootstrapping soft shrinkage (BOSS) is put forward. The proposed concept makes the best of the derivative spectra information and successfully combines the strengths of derivative spectra, CARS, SCARS, MCUVE, BOSS, and ensemble submodels. Compared with other methods in this study, this new method can establish good calibration models without increasing the complexity from the perspective of an end user. Also, overfitting issues can be prevented. Derivative1st-ECARS and Derivative1st-ESCARS have shown significant improvements in partial least regression calibration based on the experiments of three datasets. The proposed concept shows great potential of the chemometrics approaches applied to infrared data in multivariate calibration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal of Chemometrics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello R Markdown</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/talks/2020-12-01-r-rmarkdown/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Dec 2020 21:13:14 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/talks/2020-12-01-r-rmarkdown/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;r-markdown&#34;&gt;R Markdown&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is an R Markdown document. Markdown is a simple formatting syntax for authoring HTML, PDF, and MS Word documents. For more details on using R Markdown see &lt;a href=&#34;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com&#34;&gt;http://rmarkdown.rstudio.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can embed an R code chunk like this:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34; data-lang=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;summary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;cars&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;##      speed           dist       &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;##  Min.   : 4.0   Min.   :  2.00  &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;##  1st Qu.:12.0   1st Qu.: 26.00  &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;##  Median :15.0   Median : 36.00  &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;##  Mean   :15.4   Mean   : 42.98  &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;##  3rd Qu.:19.0   3rd Qu.: 56.00  &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;##  Max.   :25.0   Max.   :120.00&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;fit&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;&amp;lt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;lm&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;dist&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;~&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;speed&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;data&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;cars&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;fit&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;## &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;## Call:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;## lm(formula = dist ~ speed, data = cars)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;## &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;## Coefficients:&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;## (Intercept)        speed  &lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;c1&#34;&gt;##     -17.579        3.932&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;h1 id=&#34;including-plots&#34;&gt;Including Plots&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can also embed plots. See Figure &lt;a href=&#34;#fig:pie&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt; for example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;highlight&#34;&gt;&lt;pre tabindex=&#34;0&#34; class=&#34;chroma&#34;&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-r&#34; data-lang=&#34;r&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;par&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;mar&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;))&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;pie&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;280&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;60&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;20&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;Sky&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;Sunny side of pyramid&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;Shady side of pyramid&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;col&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;nf&#34;&gt;c&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;#0292D8&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;#F7EA39&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;s&#34;&gt;&amp;#39;#C4B632&amp;#39;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;),&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;  &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;init.angle&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;m&#34;&gt;-50&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;n&#34;&gt;border&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;o&#34;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&#34;kc&#34;&gt;NA&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;line&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;cl&#34;&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;p&#34;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;div class=&#34;figure&#34;&gt;
&lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:3435/talks/2020-12-01-r-rmarkdown/index.en_files/figure-html/pie-1.png&#34; alt=&#34;A fancy pie chart.&#34; width=&#34;672&#34; /&gt;
&lt;p class=&#34;caption&#34;&gt;&lt;span id=&#34;fig:pie&#34;&gt;&lt;/span&gt;Figure 1: A fancy pie chart.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>High-level Fusion Coupled with Mahalanobis Distance Weighted (MDW) Method for Multivariate Calibration</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/publications/high-level-fusion-coupled-with-mahalanobis-distance-weighted-mdw-method-for-multivariate-calibration/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/publications/high-level-fusion-coupled-with-mahalanobis-distance-weighted-mdw-method-for-multivariate-calibration/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Near infrared spectra (NIR) technology is a widespread detection method with high signal to noise ratio (SNR) while has poor modeling interpretation due to the overlapped features. Alternatively, mid-infrared spectra (MIR) technology demonstrates more chemical features and gives a better explanation of the model. Yet, it has the defects of low SNR. With the purpose of developing a model with plenty of characteristics as well as with higher SNR, NIR and MIR technologies are combined to perform high-level fusion strategy for quantitative analysis. A novel chemometrical method named as Mahalanobis distance weighted (MDW) is proposed to integrate NIR and MIR techniques comprehensively. Mahalanobis distance (MD) based on the principle of spectral similarity is obtained to calculate the weight of each sample. Specifically, the weight is assigned to the inverse ratio of the corresponding MD. Besides, the proposed MDW method is applied to NIR and MIR spectra of active ingredients in deltamethrin and emamectin benzoate formulations for quantitative analysis. As a consequence, the overall results show that the MDW method is promising with noticeable improvement of predictive performance than individual methods when executing high-level fusion for quantitative analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific Reports&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new strategy of applying modeling indicator determined method to high-level fusion for quantitative analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/publications/a-new-strategy-of-applying-modeling-indicator-determined-method-to-high-level-fusion-for-quantitative-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/publications/a-new-strategy-of-applying-modeling-indicator-determined-method-to-high-level-fusion-for-quantitative-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A novel method, named as modeling indicator determined (MID) method, based on two model evaluation parameters i.e., root mean square error of prediction (RMSEP) and ratio performance deviation (RPD), is proposed to employ high-level fusion for quantitative analysis. The two MID methods of root mean square error of prediction weighted (RMSEPW) method and ratio performance deviation weighted (RPDW) method are put forward on the basis of the model evaluation indicators from the individual models. Performance of RMSEPW method and RPDW method are evaluated in terms of the predictive ability of root mean square error of prediction for fusion (RMSEPf) through the fused models. The two MID methods are applied to UV–visible (UV–vis), near infrared (NIR) and mid-infrared (MIR) spectral data of active ingredient in pesticide, and gas chromatography-mass spectrometer (GC–MS) and NIR spectral data of n-heptane in chemical complex for high-level fusion. Moreover, the results are compared with the individual methods. As a result, the overall results show that the two MID methods are promising with significant improvement of predictive performance for high-level fusion when executing quantitative analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spectrochimica Acta Part A: Molecular and Biomolecular Spectroscopy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A modification of the bootstrapping soft shrinkage approach for spectral variable selection in the issue of over-fitting, model accuracy and variable selection credibility</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/publications/a-modification-of-the-bootstrapping-soft-shrinkage-approach-for-spectral-variable-selection-in-the-issue-of-over-fitting-model-accuracy-and-variable-selection-credibility/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/publications/a-modification-of-the-bootstrapping-soft-shrinkage-approach-for-spectral-variable-selection-in-the-issue-of-over-fitting-model-accuracy-and-variable-selection-credibility/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this study, we proposed a new computational method stabilized bootstrapping soft shrinkage approach (SBOSS) for variable selection based on bootstrapping soft shrinkage approach (BOSS) which can enhance the analysis of chemical interest from the massive variables among the overlapped absorption bands. In SBOSS, variable is selected by the index of stability of regression coefficients instead of regression coefficients absolute value. In each loop, a weighted bootstrap sampling (WBS) is applied to generate sub-models, according to the weights update by conducting model population analysis (MPA) on the stability of regression coefficients (RC) of these sub-models. Finally, the subset with the lowest RMSECV is chosen to be the optimal variable set. The performance of the SBOSS was evaluated by one simulated dataset and three NIR datasets. The results show that SBOSS can select the fewer variables and supply the least RMSEP and latent variable number of the PLS model with the best stability comparing with methods of Monte Carlo uninformative variables elimination (MCUVE), genetic algorithm (GA), competitive reweighted sampling (CARS), stability of competitive adaptive reweighted sampling (SCARS) and BOSS.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spectrochimica Acta Part A: Molecular and Biomolecular Spectroscopy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An ensemble variable selection method for vibrational spectroscopic data analysis</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/publications/an-ensemble-variable-selection-method-for-vibrational-spectroscopic-data-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/publications/an-ensemble-variable-selection-method-for-vibrational-spectroscopic-data-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wavelength selection is a critical factor for pattern recognition of vibrational spectroscopic data. Not only does it alleviate the effect of dimensionality on an algorithm&amp;rsquo;s generalization performance, but it also enhances the understanding and interpretability of multivariate classification models. In this study, a novel partial least squares discriminant analysis (PLSDA)-based wavelength selection algorithm, termed ensemble of bootstrapping space shrinkage (EBSS), has been devised for vibrational spectroscopic data analysis. In the algorithm, a set of subsets are generated from a data set using random sampling. For an individual subset, a feature space is determined by maximizing the expected 10-fold cross-validation accuracy with a weighted bootstrap sampling strategy. Then an ensemble strategy and a sequential forward selection method are applied to the feature spaces to select characteristic variables. Experimental results obtained from analysis of real vibrational spectroscopic data sets demonstrate that the ensemble wavelength selection algorithm can reserve stable and informative variables for the final modeling and improve predictive ability for multivariate classification models.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;RSC advances&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Towards improvement in prediction of iodine value in edible oil system based on chemometric analysis of portable vibrational spectroscopic data mutations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/publications/towards-improvement-in-prediction-of-iodine-value-in-edible-oil-system-based-on-chemometric-analysis-of-portable-vibrational-spectroscopic-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/publications/towards-improvement-in-prediction-of-iodine-value-in-edible-oil-system-based-on-chemometric-analysis-of-portable-vibrational-spectroscopic-data/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Iodine value (IV) is a significant parameter to illustrate the quality of edible oil. In this study, three portable spectroscopy devices were employed to determine IV in mixed edible oil system, a new Micro-Electro-Mechanical-System (MEMS) Fourier Transform Infrared Spectrometer (MEMS-FTIR), a MicroNIRTM1700 and an i-Raman Plus-785S. Quantitative model was built by Partial least squares (PLS) regression model and four variable selection methods were applied before PLS model, which are Monte Carlo uninformative variables elimination (MCUVE), competitive reweighted sampling (CARS), bootstrapping soft shrinkage approach (BOSS) and variable combination population analysis (VCPA). The coefficient of determination (R2), and the root mean square error prediction (RMSEP) were used as indicators for the predictability of the PLS models. In MicroNIRTM1700 dataset, MCUVE gave the lowest RMSEP (2.3440), in MEMS-FTIR dataset, CARS showed the best performance with RMSEP (2.2185), in i-Raman Plus-785S dataset, BOSS gave the lowest RMSEP (2.5058). They all had great improvements than full spectrum PLS model. Four variable selection methods take a smaller number of variables and perform significant superiority in prediction accuracy. It was demonstrated that three new portable instruments would be suitable for the on-site determination of edible oil quality in infrared and Raman field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scientific Reports&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quantitative determination of additive Chlorantraniliprole in Abamectin preparation: Investigation of bootstrapping soft shrinkage approach by mid-infrared spectroscopy</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/publications/quantitative-determination-of-additive-chlorantraniliprole-in-abamectin-preparation-investigation-of-bootstrapping-soft-shrinkage-approach-by-mid-infrared-spectroscopy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/publications/quantitative-determination-of-additive-chlorantraniliprole-in-abamectin-preparation-investigation-of-bootstrapping-soft-shrinkage-approach-by-mid-infrared-spectroscopy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A novel method, mid-infrared (MIR) spectroscopy, which enables the determination of Chlorantraniliprole in Abamectin within minutes, is proposed. We further evaluate the prediction ability of four wavelength selection methods, including bootstrapping soft shrinkage approach (BOSS), Monte Carlo uninformative variable elimination (MCUVE), genetic algorithm partial least squares (GA-PLS) and competitive adaptive reweighted sampling (CARS) respectively. The results showed that BOSS method obtained the lowest root mean squared error of cross validation (RMSECV) (0.0245) and root mean squared error of prediction (RMSEP) (0.0271), as well as the highest coefficient of determination of cross-validation (Qcv2) (0.9998) and the coefficient of determination of test set (Q2test) (0.9989), which demonstrated that the mid infrared spectroscopy can be used to detect Chlorantraniliprole in Abamectin conveniently. Meanwhile, a suitable wavelength selection method (BOSS) is essential to conducting a component spectral analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Spectrochimica Acta Part A: Molecular and Biomolecular Spectroscopy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A novel algorithm for spectral interval combination optimization</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/publications/a-novel-algorithm-for-spectral-interval-combination-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/publications/a-novel-algorithm-for-spectral-interval-combination-optimization/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this study, a new wavelength interval selection algorithm named as interval combination optimization (ICO) was proposed under the framework of model population analysis (MPA). In this method, the full spectra are divided into a fixed number of equal-width intervals firstly. Then the optimal interval combination is searched iteratively under the guide of MPA in a soft shrinkage manner, among which weighted bootstrap sampling (WBS) is employed as random sampling method. Finally, local search is conducted to optimize the widths of selected intervals. Three NIR datasets were used to validate the performance of ICO algorithm. Results show that ICO can select fewer wavelengths with better prediction performance when compared with other four wavelength selection methods, including VISSA, VISSA-iPLS, iVISSA and GA-iPLS. In addition, the computational intensity of ICO is also economical, benefit from fewer tune parameters and faster convergence speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analytica Chimica Acta&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determination of active ingredients in matrine aqueous solutions by mid-infrared spectroscopy and competitive adaptive reweighted sampling</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/publications/determination-of-active-ingredients-in-matrine-aqueous-solutions-by-mid-infrared-spectroscopy-and-competitive-adaptive-reweighted-sampling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/publications/determination-of-active-ingredients-in-matrine-aqueous-solutions-by-mid-infrared-spectroscopy-and-competitive-adaptive-reweighted-sampling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this paper, we use MIR and variable selection techniques to determine the active ingredients of matrine aqueous solutions. Competitive adaptive reweighted sampling (CARS) was engaged to investigate effective variables and compared with full-spectrum partial least squares (PLS) regression. Results indicate that MIR is very efficient in aqueous solutions quantitative determination. In the meantime, CARS is proved to be an effective variable selection approach to eliminate spectral redundancy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Optik&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characterization of a Pesticide Formulation by Medium Wave Near-Infrared Spectroscopy with Uninformative Variable Elimination and Successive Projections Algorithm</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/publications/characterization-of-a-pesticide-formulation-by-medium-wave-near-infrared-spectroscopy-with-uninformative-variable-elimination-and-successive-projections-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/publications/characterization-of-a-pesticide-formulation-by-medium-wave-near-infrared-spectroscopy-with-uninformative-variable-elimination-and-successive-projections-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Near-infrared (NIR) spectroscopy, a rapid and nondestructive analytical method, has been widely used in many fields. In this paper, medium wave near-infrared (MWNIR) was used to determine the active ingredient of a deltamethrin formulation. An uninformative variable elimination-successive projections algorithm (UVE-SPA) was employed to investigate effective variables and was compared with UVE, SPA, and full-spectrum partial least squares (PLS) regression. The results indicate that MWNIR was able to determine the pesticide active ingredient and that UVE-SPA was an efficient variable selection approach by eliminating spectral redundancy and colinearity. The developed method is a meaningful exploration in the application of near-infrared spectroscopy and provides a valuable reference on pesticide quality control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analytical Letters&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A new spectral variable selection pattern using competitive adaptive reweighted sampling combined with successive projections algorithm</title>
      <link>http://localhost:3435/publications/a-new-spectral-variable-selection-pattern-using-competitive-adaptive-reweighted-sampling-combined-with-successive-projections-algorithm/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:3435/publications/a-new-spectral-variable-selection-pattern-using-competitive-adaptive-reweighted-sampling-combined-with-successive-projections-algorithm/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The competitive adaptive reweighted sampling-successive projections algorithm (CARS-SPA) method was proposed as a novel variable selection approach to process multivariate calibration. The CARS was first used to select informative variables, and then SPA to refine the variables with minimum redundant information. The proposed method was applied to near-infrared (NIR) reflectance data of nicotine in tobacco lamina and NIR transmission data of active ingredient in pesticide formulation. As a result, fewer but more informative variables were selected by CARS-SPA than by direct CARS. In the system of pesticide formulation, a multiple linear regression (MLR) model using variables selected by CARS-SPA provided a better prediction than the full-range partial least-squares (PLS) model, successive projections algorithm (SPA) model and uninformative variables elimination-successive projections algorithm (UVE-SPA) processed model. The variable subsets selected by CARS-SPA included the spectral ranges with sufficient chemical information, whereas the uninformative variables were hardly selected.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Analyst&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joanna Gibson</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xiaotao Shen</title>
      <link></link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid></guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
