<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Metabolomics | Hong YAN</title>
    <link>http://localhost:6045/tags/metabolomics/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:6045/tags/metabolomics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Metabolomics</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:6045/media/logo_hu1d83199708a50fd4c53e13eca8c00a26_25788_300x300_fit_lanczos_3.png</url>
      <title>Metabolomics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6045/tags/metabolomics/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>An integrated analysis of the fecal metabolome and metagenome reveals the distinct effects of differentially charged nanoplastics on the gut microbiota-associated metabolites in mice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6045/publications/an-integrated-analysis-of-the-fecal-metabolome-and-metagenome-reveals-the-distinct-effects-of-differentially-charged-nanoplastics-on-the-gut-microbiota-associated-metabolites-in-mice./</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Sep 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6045/publications/an-integrated-analysis-of-the-fecal-metabolome-and-metagenome-reveals-the-distinct-effects-of-differentially-charged-nanoplastics-on-the-gut-microbiota-associated-metabolites-in-mice./</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abstract&#34;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether nanoplastics with differential charges cause intestinal impairment via distinct mechanisms remains unclear. We investigated the relationship between fecal metabolites and the gut microbiome, and potential biomarkers thereof, in mice following exposure to differentially charged polystyrene nanoplastics (PS-NPs). Metagenomic analysis revealed that exposure to differentially charged PS-NPs resulted in alterations in the abundances of Bilophila_wadsworthia, Helicobacter apodemus, and Helicobacter typhlonius. A total of 237 fecal metabolites were significantly altered in mice that exhibited intestinal impairment, and these included 10 gut microbiota-related fecal metabolites that accurately discriminated impaired intestinal samples from the control. Additionally, the specific gut microbiome-related fecal metabolite-based model approach for the prediction of intestinal impairment in mice had an area under the curve (AUC) of 1.0 in the PS (without charge) group, an AUC of 0.94 in the PS-NH2 (positive charge) group, and an AUC of 0.86 in the PS-COOH (negative charge) group. Thus, the model showed promising evaluable accuracy for the prediction of intestinal impairment induced by nanoplastics in a charge-specific manner. Our study demonstrates that the fecal metabolome of mice with intestinal impairment following exposure to differentially charged nanoplastics is associated with changes in the gut microbiome. The identified biomarkers have potential application for the detection of intestinal impairment after exposure to negative, positive, or noncharged nanomaterials.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Science of the Total Environment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Discovery of decreased ferroptosis in male colorectal cancer patients with KRAS mutations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:6045/publications/discovery-of-decreased-ferroptosis-in-male-colorectal-cancer-patients-with-kras-mutations-/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:6045/publications/discovery-of-decreased-ferroptosis-in-male-colorectal-cancer-patients-with-kras-mutations-/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;abtract&#34;&gt;Abtract&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Aberrant tumor metabolism is a hallmark of cancer in which metabolic rewiring can support tumor growth under nutrient deficient conditions. KRAS mutations occur in 35–45% of all colorectal cancer (CRC) cases and are difficult to treat. The relationship between mutant KRAS and aberrant metabolism in CRCs has not been fully explored and could be a target for intervention. We previously acquired non-targeted metabolomics data from 161 tumor tissues and 39 normal colon tissues from stage I-III chemotherapy naïve CRC patients. In this study, we revealed that only in male patients, tumors with KRAS mutations had several altered pathways that suppress ferroptosis, including glutathione biosynthesis, transsulfuration activity, and methionine metabolism. To validate this phenotype, MC38 CRC cells (KRAS&lt;sup&gt;G13R&lt;/sup&gt;) were treated with a ferroptosis inducer; RAS-selected lethal (RSL3). RSL3 altered metabolic pathways in the opposite direction to that seen in KRAS mutant tumors from male patients confirming a suppressed ferroptosis metabolic phenotype in these patients. We further validated gene expression data from an additional CRC patient cohort (Gene Expression Omnibus (GEO)), and similarly observed differences in ferroptosis-related genes by sex and KRAS status. Further examination of the relationship between these genes and overall survival (OS) in the GEO cohort showed that KRAS mutant tumors are associated with poorer 5-year OS compared to KRAS wild type tumors, and only in male patients. Additionally, high compared to low expression of GPX4, FTH1, FTL, which suppress ferroptosis, were associated with poorer 5-year OS only in KRAS mutant tumors from male CRC patients. Additionally, low compared to high expression of ACSL4 was associated with poorer OS for this group. Our results show that KRAS mutant tumors from male CRC patients have suppressed ferroptosis, and gene expression changes that suppress ferroptosis associate with adverse outcomes for these patients, revealing a novel potential avenue for therapeutic approaches.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;publication&#34;&gt;Publication&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Redox Biology&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;type&#34;&gt;Type&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Journal Articles&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
